welcome back to aush in under 3 minutes
no time for intros let's get into it
topic 4.6 introduces the societal and
cultural impacts of the market
Revolution the Innovations in technology
Agriculture and commerce we talked about
last time didn't just make goods and
businesses they changed how people lived
worked and thought about themselves
large numbers of international migrants
flooded into industrializing Northern
cities to find factory work an example
of a city growing heavily industrialized
from this being Philadelphia at the same
time a lot of Americans moved west of
the Appalachians building new
communities along the oh Ohio and
Mississippi rivers with some cities
growing here like St Louis and
Cincinnati this movement created a new
dynamic between regions as the north
urbanized while the West focused on
agriculture next let's talk about wealth
in Class Manufacturing growth led to
higher standards of living for some
folks creating a bigger middle class and
a wealthy business Elite but it should
be noted it also created a large and
growing population of laboring poor who
worked for long hours for low wages in
these factories life was better for some
but definitely not for all as for gender
and family roles with the rise of
factories many Americans both men and
women stopped relying on farming to
survive instead they worked to produce
goods for distant markets this shift
brought about new ideas of gender roles
women especially were expected to stay
home and embrace domestic ideals which
emphasize the separation of Public Work
life for men and private home life for
women not everybody was happy about this
on the screen now are some AP style
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers up on the
screen
now please follow my socials and I will
see you in the next next one